在这个可选部分中，我想要做的是重新审视特征值和特征值的概念
In this optional section what I want to do is revisit the concept of eigenvalues and
特征向量，如果你忘记了它们是什么。它们是我们的概念
eigenvectors, in case you’ve forgotten what they are. They are a concept that we’re
在下一部分需要。那么让我们考虑一个简单的线性代数
going to need in the next segment. So let’s consider a simple linear algebra
案件。我们有一个向量，v。它是一个Nx1向量，我们要将它预先乘以a
case. We have a vector, v. It’s an Nx1 vector, and we’re going to pre-multiply it by a
方阵矩阵NxN，结果当然是矢量，Nx1矢量。
square matrix NxN, and the result will of course be a vector, an Nx1 vector.
现在对于每个矩阵'A'，有N个向量，其方向不变A.
Now for every matrix ‘A’, there are N vectors whose direction is unchanged by A.
这意味着向量v和向量vprime将彼此平行。还有这些
That means the vector v and the vector v prime will be parallel to each other. And these
我们称之为特征向量的向量。现在，虽然矢量v和矢量
vectors we refer to as eigenvectors. Now, although the vector v and the vector
vprime将是平行的，它们可能不一定是相同的长度。所以长度
v prime will be parallel, they may not be necessarily the same length. So the length
通过对应于特征向量的特征值来缩放。
is scaled by the eigenvalue that corresponds to the eigenvector.
这就是很多话。让我们看一下实际中的图形示例。
So that’s a lot of words. Let’s look at a graphical example of this in practice.
我们选择了一个非常简单的A矩阵;它是一个2乘2的矩阵，因此会有两个特征向量
We’ve chosen a very simple A matrix; it’s a 2 by 2 matrix, so there will be two eigenvectors
和特征值。你可以看到一个特征值即将到来......现在。那就是
and eigenvalues. And you can see an eigenvalue just about coming up … now. That’s the
红色矢量，输入矢量和蓝色输出矢量平行的情况
case where the red vector, the input vector, and the blue output vector are parallel to
另一个。还有一个......现在。请注意，它们彼此平行
one another. There’s another one … now. Notice that they are parallel to each other
但它们的长度不一样。所以红色矢量的长度与
but they’re not the same length. So the ratio of the length of the red vector to the
蓝色矢量是特征值。所以术语特征向量......它是德国人
blue vector is the eigenvalue. So the term eigenvector … it’s a German
字和它意味着'自己的矢量'。它是属于矩阵的特殊向量。
word and it means ‘own vector’. It’s a special vector that belongs to the matrix.
所以我们可以编写几个方程式。首先，我们可以使用这个等式
So there are a couple of equations that we can write. First of all we can use the equation
我们之前有过：v乘以矩阵A给出了输出向量vprime。
that we had before: that v multiplied by the matrix A gives us the output vector v prime.
在特殊情况下，当它们平行时，它们就会被标量联系起来;
And in the particular case when they’re parallel then they are related by a scalar;
这两个矢量是平行的，只是它们的长度不同。所以我们可以代表那个
that the two vectors are parallel, only their length is different. So we can represent that
通过标量因子lambda，它是一个特征值。因此，如果这两个方程式为真，我们就可以
by the scalar factor lambda, which is an eigenvalue. So if these two equations are true we can
写下这个，我们正在通过一些数学。我们对此不感兴趣
write this, and we’re following through some maths. We’re not interested in the
在v=0的情况下，我们对A减去lambda的行列式的情况感兴趣，
case where v=0, we’re interested in the case where the determinant of A minus lambda,
I，等于0.因此，如果我们可以为任何矩阵编写该表达式，那么它很容易
I, is equal to 0. So if we can write that expression for any matrix, it’s easy for
一个2乘2的情况，3乘3更难，对于更大的矩阵非常非常困难，
a 2 by 2 case, more difficult for 3 by 3, very, very difficult for bigger matrices,
我们可以解决特征值的问题;这些lambda值。
and we can solve that for the values of the eigenvalues; these lambda values.
一旦我们得到了lambda的值，我们可以将它们替换为上面的等式，然后求解
Once we have values for lambda we can substitute them into the equations above and then solve
对于特征向量。现在有无数个特征向量
for the eigenvector. Now there are an infinite number of eigenvectors
对应于每个特征值，因此通常我们选择具有单位的特征向量
corresponding to each eigenvalue, so typically we choose eigenvectors that have got a unit
长度。这是一个额外的约束，可以帮助我们选择一个特征向量。
length. That’s an additional constraint that helps us choose just a single eigenvector.
我们将用一个简单的例子来证明这一点：使用2乘2矩阵。
We’ll demonstrate this with a simple example: with a 2 by 2 matrix.
该矩阵的特征值仅使用MATLAB内置函数eig给出。我们
The eigenvalues of this matrix are given simply using the MATLAB built-in function eig. We
看到两个特征值是1和-2。找到特征向量更多一点
see the two eigenvalues are 1 and -2. To find the eigenvectors is a little bit more
复杂。我们必须从函数eig和第一个输出中分配两个输出参数
complex. We have to assign two output arguments from the function eig, and the first output
我已经分配给矩阵x的参数有两列。第一列是
argument which I’ve assigned to the matrix x has got two columns. The first column is
第一个特征向量。第二列是第二个特征向量。和特征值
the first eigenvector. The second column is the second eigenvector. And the eigenvalues
现在沿着输出矩阵e的对角线排列。
now are arranged along the diagonal of the output matrix e.
特征向量的一个基本属性是当它被原始变换时
A fundamental property of the eigenvector is that when it is transformed by the original
矩阵，它与自身平行。我们来试试吧。
matrix, it is parallel to itself. Let’s test that.
原始矩阵A，我们将它乘以第一个特征向量
The original matrix A, and we multiply it by the first eigenvector which is the first
矩阵x的列。我们看到结果向量确实与特征向量平行，
column of the matrix x. We see that the resulting vector is indeed parallel to the eigenvector,
它具有完全相同的幅度。它被缩放为1，这就是它的值
and it has exactly the same magnitude. It’s been scaled by 1, and that is the value of
第一个特征值。因此，乘以矩阵A的特征向量是平行于矩阵A的向量
the first eigenvalue. So the eigenvector multiplied by the matrix A is a vector parallel to the
比例因子为1的特征向量。事实上，它是原始的特征向量。
eigenvector with a scale factor of 1. So it is, in fact, the original eigenvector.
让我们用另一个特征向量来尝试，这是矩阵x的第二列。
Let’s try it with the other eigenvector, which is the second column of the matrix x.
我们现在看到结果确实与第二个特征向量平行，但它已经存在
We see now that the result is indeed parallel to the second eigenvector, but it’s been
按-2缩放，-2是矩阵A的第二个特征值。
scaled by -2, and -2 is the second eigenvalue of the matrix A.